<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hardware on Anh&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.aaanh.com/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hardware on Anh&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.aaanh.com/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Barebone Dedicated ML Server</title>
      <link>https://blog.aaanh.com/posts/setting-up-a-barebone-ml-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.aaanh.com/posts/setting-up-a-barebone-ml-server/</guid>
      <description>I sure hope that I will make-even with this investment 💸</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-purchase&#34;&gt;The Purchase&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in July 2, after a bi-weekly report on my research progress to the group, I headed to eBay to buy a dedicated GPU for the machine learning tasks that I am performing. The reason, to quell my predictable buyer&amp;rsquo;s remorse, was to have a separate accelerator card from my workstation that runs on my homelab server instead. This card would need to have a (more) massive physical memory than the measly 8GB that my GTX 1080 has and quite a lot cheaper to actually justify the purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After digging around for few hours, I stumbled upon the NVidia Tesla M40 GPU. It is a data-center class GPU based on the &lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;axwell architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the specifications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Attribute&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Value&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GPU Architecture&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NVIDIA Maxwell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CUDA Cores&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3072&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Single-Precision Perf&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7 TFlops w/ NVIDIA GPU Boost&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Double-Precision Perf&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.2 TFlops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GPU Memory&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;24 GB GDDR5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Memory Bandwidth&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;288 GB/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Interface&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PCIe 3.0 x16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Max Power Consumption&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250 W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cooling&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Passive&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it is a 7-years-old GPU, considering the price of &lt;code&gt;US$179&lt;/code&gt; and three-times the GPU memory of my GTX 1080, I was quite sold on the idea of getting it. The very significant outcome is that I would be able to train on larger batch sizes and perform more aggressive feature engineering tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-delivery-rant-skip-ahead&#34;&gt;The Delivery (rant, skip ahead)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I smelled an absolute dogshit stench combined with fermented fishiness that it was utter horseshit. First, it came from the fact that I had never provided any signature for any delivery. Second, there was no delivery attempt, no phone calls, no SMS. But I checked the vicinity of the house anyway just to be sure. To no one&amp;rsquo;s surprise, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t there. I checked the tracking on the website and it still said delivered. WTF?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning, I called Intelcom&amp;rsquo;s customer support. It was not easy finding the customer support number either, because there was (and I guarantee still is) nothing listed on the official website. What a fucking shady business that operates on anti-consumerism. Anyway, I waited 20 minutes on a line until I finally got transferred to an agent. The problem seemed to be an incorrect shipping address on the system &lt;code&gt;?? 🙂 ??&lt;/code&gt;. Whatever I&amp;rsquo;d just provide again the correct address and it&amp;rsquo;d be good (right?) and the delivery was still scheduled for Monday. Came Monday, an e-mail came around 4:00 PM saying that the GPU would be delivered from 5:00 PM to 10:00 PM. Said time period came, and I got a call from the delivery person asking for the correct address. What the fuck? Didn&amp;rsquo;t I just correct it on Sunday? Was I sleep-dialing customer support in my dream? Okay fine, I gave the person the correct address and the motherfucker literally had the gall to say that it was too far away (30 minutes) from his location so he didn&amp;rsquo;t want to deliver (????). I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, but ain&amp;rsquo;t the delivery time between 5 to 10? It was fucking 5:30 PM at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be abridged and shortened, I dealt with customer support for 2 additional times on the phone, each lasting around 30-40 minutes just to harass them to do the right thing or else I would report their ass to kingdom come with Quebec Consumer Protection Office and drag their faces through the mud on Better Business Bureau. And it motherfucking worked. I finally got the GPU on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-installation&#34;&gt;The Installation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After installing the card in my server, I realized that the PSU didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough power (450 W) to run the whole system with the M40 GPU. So, I ran to the nearest Canada Computers and picked up a 650 W PSU. I had to saw off the second CPU power connector clip in order to fit the card&amp;rsquo;s power slot. And&amp;hellip; It still didn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perusing the great interweb for an hour or so, I came across a YouTube video that said I would need to enable something-something more than 4-GB decoding(?) in BIOS for it to work. The main problem was I had been running the server headlessly. That is, only through SSH and no user I/O whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this, I devised 2 options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a CPU with iGPU (my current one doesn&amp;rsquo;t have one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a cheap-ass GPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For option, the most sensible thing was to get a Ryzen 3200G (I am running on an AMD motherboard). But it costs around 300 dollary-doos. On the other hand, a cheap-ass GPU would only cost me 99 Canadian rupees in total, so I went for the latter and bought a Radeon card off Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Card arrived. BIOS configured. System booted to OS. And working fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-nvidia-installation&#34;&gt;The NVIDIA Installation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The card would totally not work if there ain&amp;rsquo;t any drivers, especially for machine learning that utilizes those sweet CUDA cores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first disabled the default Nouveau driver:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo su
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;touch /etc/modprobe.d/blacklist-nouveau.conf
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;echo -e &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blacklist nouveau\noptions nouveau modeset=0&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/modprobe.d/blacklist-nouveau.conf
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;update-initramfs -u
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;reboot
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, I installed the CUDA Toolkit using the Runfile method for easy clap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;wget https://developer.download.nvidia.com/compute/cuda/11.7.0/local_installers/cuda_11.7.0_515.43.04_linux.run
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo sh cuda_11.7.0_515.43.04_linux.run
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, I installed &lt;code&gt;anaconda&lt;/code&gt; (for demo only, please refer to Anaconda official website for latest downloads):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;wget https://repo.anaconda.com/archive/Anaconda3-2022.05-Linux-x86_64.sh &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; bash Anaconda3-2022.05-Linux-x86_64.sh
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that, I created a new environment, installed Jupyter Notebook and dependencies. And finally, I ran the first ever training (pictured below). I made sure to monitor the GPU usage through &lt;code&gt;nvidia-smi&lt;/code&gt; to verify if it was utilizing the GPU, not the CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;afterwords&#34;&gt;Afterwords&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the whole process, I spent around &lt;code&gt;CA$350&lt;/code&gt; in total for the GPU + compatible components + other efforts. Comparing that one-time price tag (electricity excluded) to Google Colab (&lt;code&gt;CA$15&lt;/code&gt; a month if I remember correctly), I should be able to breakeven in 2 years. However, it should be taken into considerations that Google Colab has timeouts and the GPU instance provided is not guaranteed, so on a good day, you might get A100 or V100, but on a bad day, you would get the whimpy K80. Adding more to the variance, you are also dependent on the storage space of your Google Drive to store models and data, which adds 5 - 15 dollars a month for a usable amount of storage. Thus, bringing down the breakeven period to simply less than 1 year of continuous usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the near future, I would want to experiment with distributed machine learning setup between the server and my workstation to see if it has any larger potential with performance gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subjectively, I think the effort was worthwhile. Though, it would have been way better if it was not for Intelcom. I&amp;rsquo;m calling that shitty company out. Keep that in your mind: Intelcom is bad.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost Had to RMA My Spanking New MacBook</title>
      <link>https://blog.aaanh.com/posts/almost-had-to-rma-my-macbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.aaanh.com/posts/almost-had-to-rma-my-macbook/</guid>
      <description>But I managed to recover everyting in the end 😂</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; the curiosity finally killed the cat. Recently, I installed Asahi Linux on my M1 Pro Macbook — my mission critical daily carry system without a flipping care in the world. It worked surprisingly well, no problems whatsoever, but I found it to be not as useful as I would have imagined. The problem didn&amp;rsquo;t lie with the engineering or stability of the Asahi Linux project, but rather it lied with the general support for Linux systems on ARM chip, especially for Arch-based distributions. Everything was fine but because of the lack of feature support, 5 hours ago, I decided to nuke the dual boot partition and reclaim the disk space, then reinstall macOS altogether because the OS was running a bit slow and hotter than usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without searching online beforehand, I did a full wipe of whatever partitions there were on the SSD. And that right there was the gateway drug down the rabbit hole of whatever the heck Apple was doing to configure their filesystem and disk management, with the sparkling cameos of useless answers on the Apple discussion forums by wannabe gurus and quantum pseudo tech literate self-acclaimed know-it-alls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internal SSD of my MacBook before I solved the shenanigan, caused by blindly nuking the partitions is as followed: - disk0: 500GB — this is the physical disk total capacity - disk0s1: 500MB — GUID Partition Table - Free Space: 4xxGB — the weird-ass void - disk0s2: 2GB — the recovery partition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I deleted both the macOS (~400GB) and Linux partitions (~100GB) with the command from the Terminal in Recovery boot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;diskutil eraseVolume free free disk0s#
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I came across this erase command from an Asahi Linux stackoverflow post in which the OP also wanted to nuke the disk like myself. However, that was the end of the story on the post without the &amp;ldquo;what to do after you nuke&amp;rdquo; instructions. Well, I thought to myself, if there&amp;rsquo;s no sequel to this post, then the subsequent process should be easy enough. Aaaand, I was dead wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The yeet of the SSD partitions leave behind the void which just could not be detected by the MacOS installer nor the graphical tool (diskutil). To make it detectable again, I had to do the most illogical thing which is expanding disk0s1 which was apparently the &amp;ldquo;GUID Partition Table&amp;rdquo;. It does not make sense because normally this partition just stores the partition table, not the whole usable partition space. But, before I came across this solution, I thought to myself, &amp;ldquo;what the heck, last resort, last ditch effort before I need to send in the laptop for RMA anyway.&amp;rdquo; Turns out, Apple&amp;rsquo;s ways of performing seemingly regular processes are &lt;em&gt;built different&lt;/em&gt;, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A note before I end this blog, I have already tried wiping ALL partitions but they are all locked by kernel (process 0). Heck, I even tried killing the kernel 🤪 process that&amp;rsquo;s using the partitions. In my defense, I was booting from a USB so killing the kernel on the internal SSD is justifiable course of action, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after expanding that GUID partition, the installation can be continued normally without any further hiccup. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll stray away from experimental software for now 😅 as this problem took a huge chunk of my time for troubleshooting&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to go only MacBook and nothing else</title>
      <link>https://blog.aaanh.com/posts/trying-to-go-only-macbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.aaanh.com/posts/trying-to-go-only-macbook/</guid>
      <description>Road warrior but in cafe shops.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Around the end of December 2021, I spent most of my internship salary on a MacBook Pro 16-in. (2021) with the base specs of M1 Pro 10-Core CPU, 16-Core GPU, 16GB Unified Memory, and 512GB SSD. The purchase was and probably still is the largest single spending I have ever made and I sat on that decision ever since the first M1 was released. I glad I broiled and boiled the purchase over and over because that delay finally coincided with the release of the M1 Pro line-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2019, around 3-4 months before COVID hit worldwide pandemic status, I sheepishly decided that I should go on a journey to minimalize my tech life. I tried to achieve this by selling off my main desktop workstation to my good friend in Vancouver and reverted back to only using the MacBook Pro 13-in (Mid 2014). I thought it was all that I needed and it really was. I was able to do everything with the exception of heavy gaming on the machine. Additionally, it had a nice compact size that made bringing it everywhere I went an absolute bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, it all went haywire. After a trip visiting my relative downtown, back when I was living near the edge of civilization at the college dorm, it started to behave weirdly. The fan kicked into 100% full swing all the time, the CPU got throttled to sub-1.0GHz speed, the I/O was unresponsive, and any attempt at doing anything was practically in vain. Luckily for me, I had a spare laptop in storage, but I still need to transfer whatever data I had left on the MBP m-2014 and the experience was painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going through this ordeal, I felt utterly betrayed by the tool I had placed my trust on. I thought I could simply get by with just a laptop, like the good old days, and focus on my study. But damn, the laptop could not have broken down at a better time: first research project with lots of code runtime, an engineering project with Arduino that I was the programmer, and of course, COVID happened. My backup laptop worked fine and great and all, but it was a Dell Precision M6000 and it was a tanky boi. The Dell barely fitted into my backpack. So, with the little amount of savings left in my account, I painstakingly ordered a ThinkPad X1 Carbon Gen. 4 to officially replace the 2 as my daily driver. It ran most of the tasks I threw at it and the slim form factor was good with the biggest trade-off is the thermals which could throttle quite significantly under heavy load, along with the high-pitched screechy fan noise. I clenched my teeth and went on with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some months later into the pandemic, I got my first part-time job into my 2nd semester at the university, doing IT stuff. With some of the first paid wages, I sold both the tanky Dell and the ThinkPad to get a MacBook Pro 13-in. (mid-2019) with the maxed out specs with the exception of storage. With some more wages, I built a new PC + a server, swearing this time, I would never even think of selling them. Then, I got my first internship and with the salary, I upgraded to the now MacBook Pro 16 with M1 Pro chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 3 months of usage, I can say that I am really impressed by the jump in quality, experience, and performance with the new MacBook Pro. The design yells back to the tried and tested form of the pre-2016 era, the keyboard is better, the functionalities are extended compared to the predecessors. And the return of the venerable innovation MagSafe brings me great joy. The HDMI port is an absolute clutch addition. The SDXC card doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter to me to be honest, but I now do have the chance to run amok and take photos with my DSLR&amp;rsquo;s again so it might come in clutch as well. Then, there&amp;rsquo;s the final piece of the puzzle, the creme de la creme, nice topping on top of everything: the high-impedance audio driver. It almost feels eerie as I had just broken into the lossless high fidelity audiophile community the beginning of last year and one of the most inconvenience is the need to carry around a DAC/amp in order to listen on my Ol&amp;rsquo; mate Sennies HD6XX. Well, this new laptop just eliminates the need for it, at least for a mobile scenario or a scenario where I shut off everything else and only have the MacBook open in front of me to do a grindset of pure focus and sprint, like for example, going ham on a development project, a study session, or a research. The freedom of choice that the new MacBook brings allows me to more easily attain what I set out to do, voided of distractions and setbacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, considering the new bells and whistles, I have decided to, once again, go MacBook only, but I am not going to sell any of my PC&amp;rsquo;s or other high-performing laptops because I think I realize that, aside of them being safety nets if anything were to happen to my MacBook (knock on wood), is those machines are perfect for setting up my lab scenarios and servers which I could use to learn new frameworks and toolings to serve my future endeavours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To close this off, there are some caveats and the biggest takeaway if someone were to consider buying the new MacBook Pro at this moment. First, the battery does not survive &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; well when connected to external displays. In my use case, I connect 1x 4K @ 60Hz + 1x 1080P @ 60Hz (+ the built-in ProMotion @ 50-60% brightness) and I use it mostly for web development tasks: writing code (on VSCode), looking up documentations (using Chrome), hot-reloading demo (on Firefox), and the occasional simple REST api (with Postman/Insomnia) automated tests. After around 30-45 minutes of usage, I notice that it drains 5-10% at most from 100% full charge, which is a bit jarring consider the highly efficient components that it operates on. However, I do think that there are still some optimizations to be done on the 3rd party software side to decrease the energy usage. Second, the M2 Pro is going to be released sooner or later this year and considering the product cycle, it would be in one&amp;rsquo;s best interest to wait for the next iteration to be released and buy that one than going for an M1 Pro at this point in time, to simply get more out of the cumbersome one-time purchase that leaves you seething for the amount of money spent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
